Michael Lew

Director of Multimedia Information Retrieval & Deep Learning, Leiden University

Summary

I am the co-head of the LIACS Computer Systems, Imagery and Media Research cluster (30+ members), which is one of the two main research groups at the computer science department at Leiden University. In addition, as a member of the LIACS Scientific Council, I am responsible for steering the general direction of computer science research at Leiden University. My group's mission is to investigate new paradigms for the retrieval and understanding of multimedia information by developing new deep learning approaches.

Currently, I'm also the Editor-In-Chief of the International Journal of Multimedia Information Retrieval (Springer), a mid-level professor at Leiden University and building the public ACM MIR-FLICKR testbed for system evaluation in media retrieval.

Experience

Member

2015 - Present

Member

2013 - Present

http://www.sigmm.org

Editor-in-Chief

2012 - Present

http://www.springer.com/13735

Chair

2011 - Present

http://www.mirsociety.org

Director of Multimedia Retrieval and Deep Learning at Leiden University

September 2005 - Present

Chair Professor of Computer Science at Tsinghua University

2003 - Present

Research and teaching in content based analysis of multimedia

Professor (mid-level, tenured, "Universitair hoofddocent") at Leiden University

January 2001 - Present

Chair

2009 - 2015 (7 years)

The ACM International Conference on Multimedia Retrieval is the leading conference on multimedia search and retrieval worldwide. It is the main forum for researchers and practitioners to share their ideas, insights, and discoveries and set future directions for the community.

General co-chair

January 2010 - December 2010 (1 year)

IEEE PCM 2010 is the major annual international conference organized as a forum for the dissemination of state-of-the-art technological advances and research results in the fields of theoretical, experimental, and applied multimedia analysis and processing.

General Chair

January 2008 - December 2008 (1 year)

ACM International Conference on Multimedia Information Retrieval

Chair at IEEE HCI2007

January 2007 - December 2007 (1 year)

IEEE International Workshop on Human Computer Interaction

Member

January 2003 - December 2006 (4 years)

General Chair at CIVR2003

January 2003 - December 2003 (1 year)

International Conference on Image and Video Retrieval

Program Chair

January 2002 - December 2002 (1 year)

First International Conference on Image and Video Retrieval, London

Researcher

September 1989 - December 1994 (5 years 4 months)

The Beckman Institute for Advanced Science and Technology at the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign is an interdisciplinary research institute devoted to leading-edge research in the physical sciences, computation, engineering, biology, behavior, cognition, and neuroscience.

Education

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign

PhD, Electrical and Computer Engineering

Michael Lew

Director of Multimedia Information Retrieval & Deep Learning, Leiden University



Contact Michael on LinkedIn